import shr1 from "./shr1.mp4"
import shr2 from "./shr2.mp4"
import shr3 from "./shr3.mp4"
import shr4 from "./shr4.mp4"
import shr5 from "./shr5.mp4"
import shr6 from "./shr6.mp4"
import shr7 from "./shr7.mp4"
import shr8 from "./shr8.mp4"
import shr9 from "./shr9.mp4"
import shr10 from "./shr10.mp4"
import shr11 from "./shr11.mp4"
import shr12 from "./shr12.mp4"
import shr13 from "./shr13.mp4"
import shr14 from "./shr14.mp4"
import shr15 from "./shr15.mp4"
import shr16 from "./shr16.mp4"
import shr17 from "./shr17.mp4"
import shr18 from "./shr18.mp4"
import shr19 from "./shr19.mp4"
import shr20 from "./shr20.mp4"
import shr21 from "./shr21.mp4"
import shr22 from "./shr22.mp4"
import shr23 from "./shr23.mp4"
import shr24 from "./shr24.mp4"
import shr25 from "./shr25.mp4"
import shr26 from "./shr26.mp4"
import shr27 from "./shr27.mp4"
import shr28 from "./shr28.mp4"
import shr29 from "./shr29.mp4"
import shr30 from "./shr30.mp4"
import shr31 from "./shr31.mp4"
import shr32 from "./shr32.mp4"
import shr33 from "./shr33.mp4"
import shr34 from "./shr34.mp4"
import shr35 from "./shr35.mp4"
import shr36 from "./shr36.mp4"
import shr37 from "./shr37.mp4"
import shr38 from "./shr38.mp4"
import shr39 from "./shr39.mp4"
import shr40 from "./shr40.mp4"
import shr41 from "./shr41.mp4"
import shr42 from "./shr42.mp4"
import shr43 from "./shr43.mp4"
import shr44 from "./shr44.mp4"
import shr45 from "./shr45.mp4"
import shr46 from "./shr46.mp4"
import shr47 from "./shr47.mp4"
import shr48 from "./shr48.mp4"
import shr49 from "./shr49.mp4"
import shr50 from "./shr50.mp4"
import shr51 from "./shr51.mp4"
import shr52 from "./shr52.mp4"
import shr53 from "./shr53.mp4"
import shr54 from "./shr54.mp4"
import shr55 from "./shr55.mp4"
import shr56 from "./shr56.mp4"
import shr57 from "./shr57.mp4"
import shr58 from "./shr58.mp4"
import shr59 from "./shr59.mp4"
import shr60 from "./shr60.mp4"
import shr61 from "./shr61.mp4"
import shr62 from "./shr62.mp4"
import shr63 from "./shr63.mp4"
import shr64 from "./shr64.mp4"
import shr65 from "./shr65.mp4"
import shr66 from "./shr66.mp4"
import shr67 from "./shr67.mp4"
import shr68 from "./shr68.mp4"
import shr69 from "./shr69.mp4"
import shr70 from "./shr70.mp4"
import shr71 from "./shr71.mp4"
import shr72 from "./shr72.mp4"
import shr73 from "./shr73.mp4"
import shr74 from "./shr74.mp4"
import shr75 from "./shr75.mp4"
import shr76 from "./shr76.mp4"
import shr77 from "./shr77.mp4"
import shr78 from "./shr78.mp4"
import shr79 from "./shr79.mp4"
import shr80 from "./shr80.mp4"
import shr81 from "./shr81.mp4"
import shr82 from "./shr82.mp4"






export const shrrek = [
    {
        id: 951,
        videoFile: shr82,
        rusQuestion: "исправить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to correct something or make something right",
        answer: "rectify",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 950,
        videoFile: shr81,
        rusQuestion: "нарцисс",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a yellow, bell-shaped flower with a long stem that is commonly seen in the spring",
        answer: "daffodil",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 949,
        videoFile: shr80,
        rusQuestion: "флейта",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a tube-shaped musical instrument with a hole that you blow across at one end while holding the tube out horizontally to one side",
        answer: "flute",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 948,
        videoFile: shr79,
        rusQuestion: "порхать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to fly or move quickly and lightly: ",
        answer: "flit",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 947,
        videoFile: shr78,
        rusQuestion: "логанова ягода",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small, red fruit, similar to a raspberry, or the tall plant on which it grows",
        answer: "loganberry",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 946,
        videoFile: shr77,
        rusQuestion: "пышка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small, round type of bread with holes in one side that is often eaten hot with butter: ",
        answer: "crumpet",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 945,
        videoFile: shr76,
        rusQuestion: "ты",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "you; object form of thou; used when speaking to one person: ",
        answer: "thee",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 944,
        videoFile: shr75,
        rusQuestion: "вставка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "something that is made to go inside or into something else: ",
        answer: "insert",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 943,
        videoFile: shr74,
        rusQuestion: "раздутый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "swollen and rounded because of containing too much air, liquid, or food:",
        answer: "bloated",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 942,
        videoFile: shr73,
        rusQuestion: "тереть",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to rub something hard in order to clean it, especially using a stiff brush, soap, and water: ",
        answer: "scrub",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 941,
        videoFile: shr72,
        rusQuestion: "бродяга",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "someone who does not have a job or a house and who moves from one place to another",
        answer: "hobo",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 940,
        videoFile: shr71,
        rusQuestion: "соус",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a thick liquid eaten with food to add flavour: ",
        answer: "sauce",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 939,
        videoFile: shr70,
        rusQuestion: "спираль",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a shape made up of curves, each one above or wider than the one before:",
        answer: "spiral",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 938,
        videoFile: shr69,
        rusQuestion: "посреди",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the middle of a group of people or things:",
        answer: "midst",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 937,
        videoFile: shr68,
        rusQuestion: "пошутить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to tell a joke: ",
        answer: "crack",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 936,
        videoFile: shr67,
        rusQuestion: "вылезти из",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to avoid doing something that you have agreed to do, especially by being dishonest:",
        answer: "weasel out",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 935,
        videoFile: shr66,
        rusQuestion: "закуска",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small amount of food that is eaten between meals, or a very small meal: ",
        answer: "snack",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 934,
        videoFile: shr65,
        rusQuestion: "усталость",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "extreme tiredness: ",
        answer: "fatigue",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 933,
        videoFile: shr64,
        rusQuestion: "гарантия",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a written promise from a company to repair or replace a product that develops a fault within a particular period of time, or to do a piece of work again if it is not satisfactory: ",
        answer: "warranty",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 932,
        videoFile: shr63,
        rusQuestion: "умиротворенность",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the quality of being peaceful and calm: ",
        answer: "serenity",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 931,
        videoFile: shr62,
        rusQuestion: "вихрь",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a mass of air or water that spins around very fast and pulls objects into its empty centre",
        answer: "vortex",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 930,
        videoFile: shr61,
        rusQuestion: "болячка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "painful and uncomfortable because of injury, infection, or too much use: ",
        answer: "sore",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 929,
        videoFile: shr60,
        rusQuestion: "гноиться",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "If a cut or other injury festers, it becomes infected and produces pus: ",
        answer: "fester",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 928,
        videoFile: shr59,
        rusQuestion: "стон",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a deep, long sound showing great pain or unhappiness: ",
        answer: "groan",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 927,
        videoFile: shr58,
        rusQuestion: "голод",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a situation in which there is not enough food for a great number of people, causing illness and death, or a particular period when this happens: ",
        answer: "famine",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 926,
        videoFile: shr57,
        rusQuestion: "вложись в это спиной",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to use a lot of physical effort to try to do something:",
        answer: "put your back into it",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 925,
        videoFile: shr56,
        rusQuestion: "мародерствовать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to steal something from a place or a person by using violence, especially during war: ",
        answer: "pillage",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 924,
        videoFile: shr55,
        rusQuestion: "растяжки",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "thin lines or marks left on someone's skin after they have grown bigger quickly, for example on the skin of a woman who has been pregnant: ",
        answer: "stretch marks",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 923,
        videoFile: shr54,
        rusQuestion: "отрыжка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to allow air from the stomach to come out through the mouth in a noisy way",
        answer: "burp",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 922,
        videoFile: shr53,
        rusQuestion: "не думай об этом",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to consider that an activity is easy and not unusual:",
        answer: "think nothing of it",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 921,
        videoFile: shr52,
        rusQuestion: "скинулись",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to give some money when several people are giving money to pay for something together: ",
        answer: "chip in",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 920,
        videoFile: shr51,
        rusQuestion: "страстное желание",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a strong feeling of wanting something: ",
        answer: "craving",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 919,
        videoFile: shr50,
        rusQuestion: "рыцарский турнир",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(in the past) to fight with a lance (= a long pointed weapon) while riding on a horse, especially as a sport",
        answer: "joust",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 918,
        videoFile: shr49,
        rusQuestion: "наказывать часто и несправедливо",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to criticize, punish, or be unkind to the same person often and unfairly: ",
        answer: "pick on",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 917,
        videoFile: shr48,
        rusQuestion: "изгонять",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to send someone away, especially from their country, and not allow them to come back: ",
        answer: "banish",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 916,
        videoFile: shr47,
        rusQuestion: "указ",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an official statement that something must happen:",
        answer: "decree",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 915,
        videoFile: shr46,
        rusQuestion: "ночной горшок",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a large, round, bowl-shaped container used as a toilet at night or during an illness, in the past often kept under a bed",
        answer: "chamber pot",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 914,
        videoFile: shr45,
        rusQuestion: "макать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to put a biscuit, piece of bread, etc. into a liquid such as tea, coffee, or soup for a short time before eating it: ",
        answer: "dunk",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 913,
        videoFile: shr44,
        rusQuestion: "шкафчик",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a cupboard, often tall and made of metal, in which you can keep your possessions, and leave them for a period of time: ",
        answer: "locker",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 912,
        videoFile: shr43,
        rusQuestion: "мэр",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a person who is elected or chosen to lead the group who governs a town or city",
        answer: "mayor",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 911,
        videoFile: shr42,
        rusQuestion: "суматоха",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a lot of activity, worry, or excitement that is unnecessary or greater than the situation deserves: ",
        answer: "ado",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 910,
        videoFile: shr41,
        rusQuestion: "придурок",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a person who is physically or socially awkward or not fashionable: ",
        answer: "dork",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 909,
        videoFile: shr40,
        rusQuestion: "извиваться",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to move from side to side in an awkward way, sometimes because of nervousness, embarrassment, or pain: ",
        answer: "squirm",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 908,
        videoFile: shr39,
        rusQuestion: "по принципу служебной необходимости",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "If you tell people something ooooo, you only tell them the facts they need to know at the time they need to know them, and nothing more.",
        answer: "on a need-to-know basis",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 907,
        videoFile: shr38,
        rusQuestion: "железная Дева",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a mythical torture device, consisting of a solid iron",
        answer: "iron maiden",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 906,
        videoFile: shr37,
        rusQuestion: "мирра",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a sticky brown substance with a strong smell that is used in making perfume and incense (= a substance burned to produce a sweet smell, for example in a religious ceremony)",
        answer: "myrrh",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 905,
        videoFile: shr36,
        rusQuestion: "ладан",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a sticky substance that can be solid or in the form of a thick liquid, that produces a sweet smell when burned and comes from a tree that grows in East Africa and Asia: ",
        answer: "frankincense",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 904,
        videoFile: shr35,
        rusQuestion: "кружащийся",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "moving quickly with a twisting, circular movement, or seeming to do this: ",
        answer: "swirling",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 903,
        videoFile: shr34,
        rusQuestion: "оп",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an occasion when someone's underwear moves or is pulled up so it is uncomfortably tight around, or between the two sides of, their bottom: ",
        answer: "wedgie",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 902,
        videoFile: shr33,
        rusQuestion: "воспитывать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to take care of, feed, and protect someone or something, especially young children or plants, and help him, her, or it to develop:",
        answer: "nurture",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 901,
        videoFile: shr32,
        rusQuestion: "кувшин",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a large, round container for liquids that has a flat base, a handle, and a very narrow raised opening at the top for pouring: ",
        answer: "pitcher",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 900,
        videoFile: shr31,
        rusQuestion: "колыбель",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small bed for a baby, especially one that moves from side to side: ",
        answer: "cradle",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 899,
        videoFile: shr30,
        rusQuestion: "мести",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to clean something, especially a floor by using a brush to collect the dirt into one place from which it can be removed: ",
        answer: "sweep",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 898,
        videoFile: shr29,
        rusQuestion: "побуждение",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a strong wish, especially one that is difficult or impossible to control:",
        answer: "urge",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 897,
        videoFile: shr28,
        rusQuestion: "убеждение",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a particular set of beliefs, especially religious ones: ",
        answer: "persuasion",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 896,
        videoFile: shr27,
        rusQuestion: "зефир",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a soft, sweet, pink or white food: ",
        answer: "marshmallow",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 895,
        videoFile: shr26,
        rusQuestion: "жарить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to cook food in an oven or over a fire: ",
        answer: "roast",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 894,
        videoFile: shr25,
        rusQuestion: "скакать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to dance around, having a noisy good time:",
        answer: "cavort",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 893,
        videoFile: shr24,
        rusQuestion: "тапочка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a type of soft, comfortable shoe for wearing inside the house: ",
        answer: "slipper",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 892,
        videoFile: shr23,
        rusQuestion: "вор в бассейне",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "To move or act energetically and rapidly",
        answer: "pool hustler",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 891,
        videoFile: shr22,
        rusQuestion: "карлик",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "in stories for children, a creature like a little man with magical powers: ",
        answer: "dwarf",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 890,
        videoFile: shr21,
        rusQuestion: "alike",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "similar to each other: ",
        answer: "alike",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 889,
        videoFile: shr20,
        rusQuestion: "искупление",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(especially in Christianity) an occasion when someone is saved from evil, suffering, etc.",
        answer: "redemption",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 888,
        videoFile: shr19,
        rusQuestion: "недовольный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "feeling unhappy because you want better treatment or an improved situation: ",
        answer: "discontented",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 887,
        videoFile: shr18,
        rusQuestion: "сюда",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to or towards this place: ",
        answer: "hither",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 886,
        videoFile: shr17,
        rusQuestion: "нерест",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to cause something new, or many new things, to grow or start suddenly: ",
        answer: "spawn",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 885,
        videoFile: shr16,
        rusQuestion: "легкий стук",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a series of quick, light knocking sounds:",
        answer: "pitter-patter",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 884,
        videoFile: shr15,
        rusQuestion: "пренебрегать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to not give enough care or attention to people or things that are your responsibility:",
        answer: "neglect",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 883,
        videoFile: shr14,
        rusQuestion: "грибок",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "any of various types of organisms that get their food from decaying material or other living things:",
        answer: "fungus",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 882,
        videoFile: shr13,
        rusQuestion: "разбрасывать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to spread things in an untidy way over a surface, or to be spread in an untidy way over a surface: ",
        answer: "strew",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 881,
        videoFile: shr12,
        rusQuestion: "хижина",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a very simple and small building made from pieces of wood, metal, or other materials",
        answer: "shack",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 880,
        videoFile: shr11,
        rusQuestion: "паразит",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "small animals and insects that can be harmful and are difficult to control when they appear in large numbers: ",
        answer: "vermin",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 879,
        videoFile: shr10,
        rusQuestion: "он не создан для этого",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: " not to be the right type of person for a particular job or activity:",
        answer: "cut out for",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 878,
        videoFile: shr9,
        rusQuestion: "Улыбнись и перенеси это",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to accept something bad without complaining: ",
        answer: "grin and bear it",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 877,
        videoFile: shr8,
        rusQuestion: "дурак",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a stupid person: ",
        answer: "twit",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 876,
        videoFile: shr7,
        rusQuestion: "замещать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to do someone else's work for them because they cannot or will not do it themselves:",
        answer: "fill in",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 875,
        videoFile: shr6,
        rusQuestion: "лодырь",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "someone who is lazy:",
        answer: "lazybones",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 874,
        videoFile: shr5,
        rusQuestion: "посещение",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the fact of going somewhere such as a church, school, etc. regularly: ",
        answer: "attendance",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 873,
        videoFile: shr4,
        rusQuestion: "грязный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "extremely unpleasant",
        answer: "foul",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 872,
        videoFile: shr3,
        rusQuestion: "дева",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a girl or young woman: ",
        answer: "maiden",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 871,
        videoFile: shr2,
        rusQuestion: "прислушивайся",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "used to tell someone to listen:",
        answer: "hark",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 870,
        videoFile: shr1,
        rusQuestion: "вперед",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "moving forward to a later time or a more distant (= farther away) place: ",
        answer: "onward",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    
]